A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1951
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1951
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.581
This collection consists of 13,200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library in January 1958.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
There are also architectural landscape drawings for men's dormitories, 1949; a 1935 Topographical map; and two drawings of Route 302 on Copeley Hill.
Contents List
- General Files, 1951
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 1)
  - Air Forces 1951 (Box 1)
  - Airport (Milton) (folder empty) 1951 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - General Correspondence 1951 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - Meetings 1951 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - Treasurer 1951 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Office 1951 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1951 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1951 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1951 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" 1951 (Box 2)
  - Army - General 1951 (Box 2)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J.A.G.) Office 1951 (Box 2)
  - Army ROTC - Transportation Corps 1951 (Box 2)
  - Army ROTC - Medical 1951 (Box 2)
  - Art and Architecture 1951 (Box 2)
  - Art Commission 1951 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1951 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1951 (Box 2)
  - Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1951 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1951 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1951 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - August - December 1951 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - January - July 1951 (Box 4)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1951 (Box 4)
  - Athletics - Commonwealth Day 1951 (Box 4)
  - Atlantic Union 1951 (Box 4)
  - Attorney General 1951 (Box 4)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1951 (Box 4)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 5)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 5)
  - Bibliographical Society 1951 (Box 5)
  - Biology 1951 (Box 5)
  - Biology - Blandy Farm 1951 (Box 5)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1951 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Cemetery 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Chemistry 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Electricity 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Gas 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Roads 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Telephone System 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings Program - General 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings Program - Academic Building 1951 (Box 6)
  - Buildings Program - Architects and Engineers 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Convalescent Children's Home 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Contracts 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Law Department 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Life Science Building 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Medical Buildings 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Men's Dormitories 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Natural Resources Building 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Naval Armory 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Physics 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Power Plant and Heating Mains 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Site Plans 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Student Activities Building 1951 (Box 7)
  - Buildings Program - Women's Dormitory 1951 (Box 7)
  - Bursar's Office 1951 (Box 8)
  - Byrd, Senator H. F. 1951 (Box 8)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 8)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1951 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace 1951 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching 1951 (Box 8)
  - Cavalier Daily 1951 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry 1951 (Box 9)
  - Civilian Defense 1951 (Box 9)
  - Classics 1951 (Box 9)
  - Clippings 1951 (Box 9)
  - Commerce and Economics 1951 (Box 9)
  - Commission on the Study of Higher Education in Virginia 1951 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Academic Legislation 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Administrative Committees (Miscellaneous) 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Admissions (College) 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Chaperones' 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Constitutional Government 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Hospital Administrative Policy 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Institute of Public Affairs Advisory 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Lectures 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committees - Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Processions 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Rushton Seminars 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans, and Employment 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Science Advisory 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Senate Reorganization 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Social Security for Faculty 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Tree 1951 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Women's Dormitory Name 1951 (Box 10)
  - Compulsory Education 1951 (Box 10)
  - Compulsory Education - Clippings 1951 (Box 10)
  - Council of State Governments 1951 (Box 11)
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 11)
  - Dean Hollingsworth 1951 (Box 11)
  - Dean Lewis 1951 (Box 11)
  - Dean Ferguson 1951 (Box 11)
  - Dean Mallett 1951 (Box 11)
  - Declaration of Independence - 175th Anniversary of Signing 1951 (Box 11)
  - Degrees 1951 (Box 12)
  - Development Fund 1951 (Box 12)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 12)
  - Education 1951 (Box 12)
  - Endowment - Contingency Fund 1951 (Box 12)
  - Engineering Department 1951 (Box 13)
  - Extension Division 1951 (Box 13)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 13)
  - Faculty 1951 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly-Tiffany Scholarships 1951 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ford Foundation Fellowships 1951 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright Awards 1951 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes Scholarships 1951 (Box 14)
  - Finals 1951 (Box 14)
  - Fletcher 1951 (Box 14)
  - Food Services 1951 (Box 14)
  - Foreign Affairs - July - December 1951 (Box 15)
  - Foreign Affairs - January - June 1951 (Box 15)
  - Foreign Affairs (two folders) 1951 (Box 15)
  - Forestry 1951 (Box 15)
  - Forest, Seward 1951 (Box 15)
  - Founder's Day 1951 (Box 16)
  - Fraternities 1951 (Box 16)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 16)
  - Garden Club 1951 (Box 16)
  - General Education Board 1951 (Box 16)
  - Geography 1951 (Box 16)
  - Geology 1951 (Box 16)
  - Geological Survey 1951 (Box 16)
  - Germanic Languages 1951 (Box 16)
  - Gifts and Grants 1951 (Box 16)
  - Governor's Office 1951 (Box 17)
  - Graduate Department 1951 (Box 17)
  - "Ha - He" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 17)
  - "Hf - Hz" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 17)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1951 (Box 17)
  - History 1951 (Box 17)
  - Hospital: July - December 1951 (Box 18)
  - Hospital: January - June 1951 (Box 18)
  - Honor System 1951 (Box 18)
  - Housing 1951 (Box 18)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 18)
  - India 1951 (Box 18)
  - Institute of International Education 1951 (Box 18)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations 1951 (Box 19)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1951 (Box 19)
  - Insurance 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "A" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "B" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "C" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "D" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "E" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "F" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "G" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "H" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "I" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "J" 1951 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "K" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "L" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "M" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "N" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "O" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "P" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "R" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "S" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "T" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "U" 1951 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "V" 1951 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "W" 1951 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1951 (Box 21)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 22)
  - Law School 1951 (Box 22)
  - Lectures - General 1951 (Box 22)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1951 (Box 22)
  - Lectures - Richard 1951 (Box 22)
  - Legal Matters 1951 (Box 22)
  - Legislative Program 1951 (Box 22)
  - Library 1951 (Box 23)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1951 (Box 23)
  - Library - McGregor Library 1951 (Box 23)
  - Library - Taylor Room (folder empty) 1951 (Box 23)
  - Loan Funds 1951 (Box 23)
  - Lower Division of College 1951 (Box 23)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 24)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 24)
  - "Mf - Mz" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 24)
  - Madison Hall 1951 (Box 24)
  - Marine Corps 1951 (Box 24)
  - McIntire Fund 1951 (Box 24)
  - Mary Washington College 1951 (Box 25)
  - Mary Washington College - Dockets 1951 (Box 25)
  - Mathematics 1951 (Box 25)
  - Medical Department 1951 (Box 25)
  - Military - Miscellaneous (see also Army, Navy, Marine Corps, etc.) 1951 (Box 26)
  - Samuel Miller Fund 1951 (Box 26)
  - Music - General 1951 (Box 26)
  - Music - Great Composers' Festival 1951 (Box 26)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 27)
  - National Association of State Universities 1951 (Box 27)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1951 (Box 27)
  - National Education Association 1951 (Box 27)
  - National Science Foundation 1951 (Box 27)
  - Navy 1951 (Box 27)
  - Navy - ROTC 1951 (Box 27)
  - Naval ROTC -Prompted and mimeographed communications 1951 (Box 27)
  - Newcomb, J. L. 1951 (Box 27)
  - Nursing Education 1951 (Box 27)
  - Nursing School 1951 (Box 27)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 27)
  - Oak Ridge 1951 (Box 27)
  - "Pa - Pe" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 28)
  - "Pf - Pz" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 28)
  - Patents (folder empty) 1951 (Box 28)
  - Personnel 1951 (Box 28)
  - Personnel and Placement Office 1951 (Box 28)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1951 (Box 28)
  - Philosophy 1951 (Box 28)
  - Physical Education 1951 (Box 28)
  - Physics 1951 (Box 28)
  - Photographs 1951 (Box 28)
  - Political Science 1951 (Box 28)
  - Princeton Organization 1951 (Box 28)
  - Printing 1951 (Box 28)
  - President's Council 1951 (Box 28)
  - Pritchett 1951 (Box 28)
  - Psychology 1951 (Box 28)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous (folder empty) 1951 (Box 29)
  - Questionnaires 1951 (Box 29)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 29)
  - Radio 1951 (Box 29)
  - Recommendation, Letters of 1951 (Box 29)
  - Regional Education 1951 (Box 29)
  - Registrar 1951 (Box 29)
  - Religion 1951 (Box 30)
  - Requisitions 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - General 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Army Research 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Bureau of Public Administration 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Geographical Institute 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - National Research Council 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Naval Research, General 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Naval Research, Ordnance Research Laboratory 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Public Health Service 1951 (Box 30)
  - Richmond Area University Center 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Romance Languages 1951 (Box 30)
  - Research - Rural Social Economics 1951 (Box 30)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 31)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 31)
  - Segregation 1951 (Box 31)
  - Selective Service 1951 (Box 31)
  - Senate (University) 1951 (Box 31)
  - Sigma Xi 1951 (Box 31)
  - Sociology 1951 (Box 31)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1951 (Box 31)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1951 (Box 31)
  - Southern University Conference 1951 (Box 31)
  - Speech and Drama 1951 (Box 31)
  - Speeches and Articles 1951 (Box 32)
  - State Board of Education 1951 (Box 32)
  - State Board of Health 1951 (Box 32)
  - State University Association 1951 (Box 32)
  - Statistics 1951 (Box 32)
  - Stettinius Memorial 1951 (Box 32)
  - Student Affairs 1951 (Box 32)
  - Student Health Department 1951 (Box 32)
  - Sullivan Award 1951 (Box 32)
  - Summer Session 1951 (Box 32)
  - Surplus Property 1951 (Box 32)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 32)
  - Travel 1951 (Box 32)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1951 (Box 32)
  - Treasury Department 1951 (Box 32)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 33)
  - United States Office of Education 1951 (Box 33)
  - University Houses - Applications 1951 (Box 33)
  - University News Service 1951 (Box 33)
  - University Press 1951 (Box 33)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 33)
  - Veterans 1951 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1951 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1951 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Education Association 1951 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1951 (Box 33)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1951 (Box 33)
  - Visitors - Dockets 1951 (Box 33)
  - Visitors - Mr. Anderson 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Judge Barksdale 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Black 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Carrington 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Dr. Emmett 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Garnett 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gay 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gravatt 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Howard 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Mears 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Smith 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mr. Talbott 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Wailes 1951 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Willis 1951 (Box 34)
  - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 35)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 35)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1951 (Box 35)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1951 (Box 35)